FRANCISCA SEVERINO

New York, NY

francisca.severino@gmail.com

+347-882-3009



ABOUT

I specialize in strategic design, blending systems thinking with a relentless drive for quality and innovation. With over a decade of experience across various sectors like startups, non-profits, and for-profit enterprises, I bring a proven ability to deliver exceptional customer experiences. My leadership style emphasizes results, empowering teams to excel and make a meaningful impact on business growth.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2018

PARSONS, THE NEW SCHOOL

Master of Science - MS, Strategic Design and Management

2006 - 2011

PONTIFICIA UNIVERSIDAD CATÓLICA DE CHILE

Designer, Design and Applied Arts

CORE COMPETENCIES

Design Thinking Consumer-Oriented Experiences

Microsoft Excel Entrepreneurship

Project Management Adobe Illustrator / Photoshop

Team Management NetSuite

WORK EXPERIENCE

2019 - Present

→ DATA PROJECTS MANAGER

Allied Cloud

- Lead a team of data migration specialists in executing NetSuite data migration projects for for-profit and non-profit clients.
- Design and implement robust internal processes and procedures for training, data management, and seamless migration of clients' data into NetSuite, ensuring efficiency and accuracy throughout the process.
- Foster a collaborative and efficient work environment, promoting knowledge sharing, teamwork, and professional development among team members.
- Ensure adherence to project timelines, quality standards, and data integrity throughout the migration process.

2018 - 2019

→ BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT ASSOCIATE

BE MORE

- Managed and developed BE MORE's external brand and support the business development efforts.
- Contributed to the creation of a digital solution aimed at dismantling biases through a multifaceted approach.
 This involved conducting interviews, facilitating working sessions, and organizing workshops to gather valuable information.

2017 - 2018

→ PROGRAM MANAGER & DESIGNER

The New School - Impact Entrepreneurship Initiative

- · Conduct design workshops, collaborate with project stakeholders to foster morale and support.
- · Oversee program management including pipeline management and program deployment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2016 - 2018

→ DIRECTOR OF BUSINESS RELATIONSHIPS

FreshWater Solutions

- Led the strategic development and implementation of alliances and business relationships for FreshWater Solutions, a company dedicated to bringing quality purified water to rural areas.
- Proactively identified and pursued new opportunities for partnerships to expand the reach and impact of the organization.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to align partnerships with the organization's strategic goals and objectives.

2011 - 2015

→ GLOBAL ECOSYSTEM DIRECTOR LATAM | STARTUP DIRECTOR

Socialab

- Developed innovative methodologies to assist social entrepreneurs by leveraging community insights and engaging in co-creation with entrepreneurs and users.
- Analyzed business models, value propositions, problem-solving approaches, and team management for over 100 entrepreneurs.
- Established and nurtured a supportive network for entrepreneurs, facilitating business growth and maximizing social impact.

PROJECTS & VOLUNTEERISM

2024 - Current

→ [SPARCS] SUPPORTING PARKS AND REVITALIZING COMMUNITIES STUDY

3x3 & CUNY

SPARCS is an initiative led by CUNY's Center for Systems and Community Design, focused on activating recently redesigned parks in NYC to support resident wellbeing. 3x3, a community-centered design studio is supporting by leading local design teams through a community-driven design and implementation process.

- Selected to be part of the Local Design Team for Astoria Heights Playground.
- Community-driven process to design and implement a park program that boosts resident physical and social wellbeing.

2016 - 2018

→ FINANCIAL LITERACY FACILITATOR

Qualitas of Life Foundation

Qualitas of Life Foundation is a non-profit organization that provides financial education to Hispanic individuals and their families, in order to foster their financial security and improve their standard of living

- Provide financial education workshops to the Hispanic migrant community
- Dedicated efforts to empower the most disadvantaged and marginalized individuals within the Hispanic community by promoting financial literacy, ultimately enhancing their quality of life and fostering financial security and well-being.

2018

-> FINANCIAL INCLUSION: EMPOWERING WOMEN THROUGH FINANCES

Capstone Project

During my final year at graduate school, at Parsons, I pursued my passion and personal motivations by undertaking a year-long capstone project. I focused on Financial Inclusion & Women Empowerment, driven by the belief that combining these two areas could lead to impactful results in developing tools to empower women through financial means.

- Conducted interviews and led in-person workshops to gather information on empowering women through financial means.
- · Synthesized findings and brainstormed options for co-creation and prototyping based on the gathered insights.
- Developed a Minimum Viable Product (MVP) and conducted tests to enhance the product, alongside creating an implementation roadmap for further development and deployment.